Hannah McCullough

Phoenix, AZ | (602) 903-0852 | mccullough.hannah@outlook.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Innovative full-stack web developer with skills in building applications with a user-experience approach by utilizing Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, SQL databases, and RESTful API architecture. With a customer-service, management, and athletic background, I bring strong skills in client relations, collaboration, and leadership.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Postgres, SQLite, Git, WordPress

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Housd, GitHub

Home maintenance checklist and service booking application designed with dual-user types for homeowners and service providers

- Modeled custom database schema and REST API with Active Record, Postgres, and Rails
- Created two different dashboards with routing based on user login information determining user's profile type
- Utilized Auth and bcrypt to authenticate user login and authorize user functionality based on user type

Strength Trainer, GitHub

Strength training application tracker equipped with organizational workout logging and data calculations based on user input

- Developed Rails API and Postgres back end with endpoints for users and their workouts
- User interface implemented with JavaScript/React, reactstrap, and CSS
- Authenticated users at login by encrypting identifying account information via Auth and bcrypt

Coffee Me Recipes, GitHub: Frontend | Backend

SPA to get and share coffee recipes with search and filtering tools and the capability to post new recipes

- Engineered back end using Active Record and Rails
- Implemented modern front end with JavaScript/React, Material UI, and CSS
- Designed layouts and components to provide a seamless user experience while navigating the application

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 Freelance
 Phoenix, AZ

 Web & Graphic Designer
 03/2018 – 01/2021

Designed web sites for small businesses in the Phoenix area with enhanced UI/UX, resulting in increased traffic and leads

Designed and created menus, flyers, digital catalogs, social media content, and logos using Adobe Photoshop

USAAPhoenix, AZSenior Insurance Professional09/2018 – 11/2021

• Served as a department facilitator in the Pulse initiative by communicating employee feedback and innovation to executives

• Regularly facilitated team meetings, which resulted in an overall increase in team metrics

Zappone's Italian Bistro/Z Catering

Phoenix, AZ

Manager/Marketing Coordinator

09/2014 - 09/2018

- Implemented modern marketing techniques, resulting in a sales increase of 25%
- Managed catering teams ranging from 3-8 employees, ensuring prompt and organized professional services

EDUCATION

Scottsdale Community College

01/2018 – 12/2022 Associate in Applied Science Web Development Flatiron School

11/2021 – 03/2022 Full-Stack Web Development Scottsdale Community College

08/2018 – 12/2020 Associate in Applied Science Web Design Saint Francis University/ Lake Erie College 08/2010 – 05/2014

Bachelor of Arts Psychology Athlete